

David Pham
<Full Stack Developer>

e. phamous2day@gmail.com

Github: http://github.com/phamous2day

Linkedin <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/phamdavid">https://www.linkedin.com/in/phamdavid</a>

portfolio: http://phamous2day.github.io

#### **RECENT PROJECTS**

<u>Pictionary</u>: Originally a "draw-together" app utilizing HTML5 as the canvas and leveraging Socket.IO to provide collaborative experience across computers. Added chat functionality using Node.js to make it further engaging/challenging as a Pictionary game to store "secret words" as the Pictionary topic to draw.

**Sports Map/Ticket Aggregator**: Worked on a team creating an app that maps out current matches using Google Maps and utilizing TicketMaster API to aggregate ticket purchases with corresponding matches. We had a limitation with free accounts that restrict API calls to SportsRadar API, but we offset that by learning to store and call JSON data locally.

<u>Canvas Game</u>: Objective was to create a "chase-the-goblin" game with Javascript with 32-bit sprites. I enhanced the experience by incorporating bootstrap, Google Fonts, and higher resolution sprites for a more visually-appealing experience.

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

## Year Up

Information Technology Instructor (Jan. 2015—April 2016)

- Facilitated learning through a student-centered environment, ensuring knowledge of content in Computer Hardware, Operating Systems, Project Management, and Network Infrastructure.
- Problem solved site-wide IT issues (wireless connectivity, AV equipment, intermediary between ATL and National headquarters).

## MailChimp

Customer Support Technician (Aug. 2012—July 2014)

- Consistently surpassed average monthly ticket quota by 120%.
- Replicated user issues in test environment and provided documentation to developers.

## AmeriCorps VISTA

Technology Coordinator (Feb. 2011 – Feb 2012)

- Worked in-person and remotely with over 50 staff members when computer issues occurred.
- Conceptualized and created school's first E-Yearbook using HTML and Javascript to offset traditional yearbook costs (ink, shipping, page count, etc).

# **EDUCATION**

DigitalCrafts (May 2016—Present)

University of Hawai'i at Mānoa (Aug. 2006—May 2010)

Bachelor of Arts in Journalism